Grant Cloyd MFA

Currently in Fort Worth, TX || Relocating to DC/MD/VA: Nov. 2021 (703) 472-3648 · dgcloyd@gmail.com GitHub | Blog | LinkedIn

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full-stack developer with experience in React and Rails. I have a passion for learning and enjoy working with new technologies to find sustainable solutions that are tailored to client specifications. My previous background in theater and medical education has prepared me to be a thoughtful, process-oriented collaborator with a desire to create meaningful and engaging user experiences.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

React, Javascript, Rails, Ruby, Redux, Material-UI, PostgreSQL, SQL Git/Github, Heroku, CSS, HTML

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

App Name: Here||Now - Github | Heroku | Demo

A meditation app designed for users and content creators to come together and interact with each other through guided meditations, messaging, following, favoriting, and donations while tracking and providing relevant user/creator data.

- Designed a SPA utilizing React, Redux, React Player, React Router, and the Media Recorder API to create a fast, efficient front-end user experience for audio playback and recording, state management, and client-side routing
- Incorporated ActiveStorage and utilized AWS (S3) for cloud storage.
- Created a custom database schema with a Rails RESTful API using a PosgreSQL database with secure user passwords and session cookies for maintaining user log-in status.
- Styled using Material-UI's core, styles, and icons for clean user interface with a CSS in Javascript approach to styling.

App Name: localHost - Github | Heroku | Demo

A live chat messaging app where you change your app's color themes, create chat rooms for family or adult rooms, react to user messages and view their profiles

- Employed ActionCable and Redis and designed a Rails API with PostgreSQL database to handle WebSocket protocol for live-time chatting, reactions, and chatroom updates
- Engineered front end view layer using React and ActionCableProvider with styling using Material-UI and Material Icons
- Implemented Berypt gem to ensure security of user passwords and user authorization

App Name: CoffeeFiltr – Github || Demo

A fun way to explore and find new coffee beverages. Discover, favorite, sort and filter coffee beverages by ingredients and see what you can make your own based on what you have on hand.

- Used React including the Context API and React-Router to handle data/client side routing
- Built sorting, filtering and searching options in the view layer to increase user ease and added ability to search preferences
- Developed and designed in tandem with a pair programming partner
- Designed a custom API using Rack/Sinatra to handle SQlite database queries to model layer

EXPERIENCE

TCU and UNTHSC School of Medicine

Fort Worth, TX

Associate Director: Standardized Patient Education

10/2018 - 05/2021

- Helped design and implement simulation-based healthcare curriculum for a brand-new medical school
- Led the SP program, including overseeing guidelines, screening/training of SPs, and technology resources for the school.
- Oversaw the training, management, and implementation of CAE LearningSpace software and hardware for video capture, data gathering, event management, and assessment of students, faculty, and SPs.

Val G Hemming Simulation Center(USUHS)

Silver Spring, MD 05/2015 – 09/2018

Clinical Skills Educator

03/2013 03/2010

- Trained actors and non-actors to portray Standardized Patients for medical military education and government organizations.
- Designed, implemented, and executed hundreds of events for hundreds of learners at a time

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Remote

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and React/JavaScript program

05/2021 - 08/2021

Catholic University of America

Washington, DC

05/2015

Master of Fine Arts in Acting (3 year program)

Magna Cum Laude; Hartke Scholarship Recipient

St Mary's College of Maryland

St. Mary's, MD

Bachelor of Arts in Theater, Film, and Media Studies

Magna Cum Laude; Kathy Glockner Arts Alliance Award for Theater Excellence

05/2008